KIRAN KUMAR ROY (B Tech CSE)

Bangalore | kkroy22@gmail.com | +91 9761646277 https://www.linkedin.com/in/kkroy22/

Summary:

I have **One Year Experience** in working on building machine learning models with Python and data analysis and cleaning with Java. I was also involved in building API for machine learning task using Django and Flask and Model deployment with Docker.

Professional Experience:

Nielsen (Global Information, Data and Measurement Company) Nielsen consultant via Lucida Technologies Pvt Ltd, December 2017 to present

Providing machine learning models and data analysis for the measurement of Retailer data.

- > Applying a supervised classification algorithm on the data provided by retailers of various countries.
- > Analysis of data with an unsupervised learning algorithm.
- > cleaning of retailer data.

Quantifiable results:

- > The manual processing time of two to three months is reduced to a week.
- > Helped retailers of multiple countries to speed up the onboarding process to Nielsen.

Lucida Technologies Pvt Ltd (Technology Services, Digital Services and Analytics) Machine Learning Team, December 2017 to present

Developing projects which help to build and shine together

> Building a computer vision API for correctly counting of the class of vehicle.

Quantifiable results:

> Counting became easier by the automatic sheet generation.

YottoLabs (Digital Commerce and Digital Transformations) Team Member, September 2017 to November 2017

Involved in solving problems in the food and beverage sector

- > Item report generation API
- > Time series analysis of item.

Quantifiable results:

> Accelerating the business towards innovation with Artificial Intelligence.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

Certificate for Outstanding Performance in Machine Learning - Lucida Technologies Pvt Ltd

EDUCATION:

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA – 2017 (Feb 17 to Aug 17)

BIG DATA ANALYTICS
Centre for Development of Advanced Computing
Ministry of Electronics & Information Technology (GOI)
KP – Bengaluru
560038

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY – 2016 (Aug 12 to June 16)

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING
Govind Ballabh Pant Engineering College
An Autonomous College of Government of Uttarakhand
Pauri Garhwal
246194

ARMY PUBLIC SCHOOL

CENTRAL BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION
XII 2012 PCM
X 2010 GEN

Of Note:

General Purpose skillsets that I am familiar with:

Programming language: C, Java, JavaScript, Python, R, Scala, SQL

Operating System: Batch Scripting, Shell Scripting

Version Control and Document Preparation: Git, LaTeX

Database: PostgreSQL

Big Data and Analytic: Machine Learning, Hadoop

Deployment: Docker, Flask, Django

Portfolio: At https://www.bikky.space/reactme/#/